Full Stack Software Development

ZHOUWU HUANG

15900517866

ABOUT ME

Hello! I have sixteen years of experience in software development. I have extensive experience in ERP system solutions, desktop operating system solutions, internet financial industry, internet education industry, traditional automobile manufacturing information digitalization. I am an enthusiastic software engineer passionate about technology, and I enjoy delving into and using new technologies and applying them to appropriate scenarios. I hope to have the honor of working with you!

EDUCATION

South China University of Technolog (Project 985 elite university)
Bachelor of Science (Mathematics) | September 2003 - June 2007

EXPERIENCE

HASCO Vision Technology (Shanghai) Co., Ltd. Head of Digital Development Department | November 2021 - Now

Responsibilities: I was responsible for the digital project architecture design and front-end and back-end code development, online release and operation and maintenance; optimize performance and security modules; take the lead in the development and continuous optimization of DevOps tool chain; optimize agile development process and standards, build CI/CD tool platform based on GitLab (build GitLab Runner, container image repository, Nexus repository) and micro-service architecture design; promote the separation of front and back end of the company's projects, micro-service, automation operation and maintenance, to greatly enhance the delivery capacity of digital system software. The projects mainly involve MES, AIPS, SCM, Weiw OA administrative office, financial integration, electronic salary list, rationalization proposals, enterprise certification micro-services, SAP Hana middleware, enterprise service bus, etc.

Skills: Oauth2-based SSO authentication technology, two-site three-center disaster recovery high availability technology, zero-loss release (Red-Black/Blue-Green/Canary, Nginx/Microservice traffic switching scheme design), stateless service JWT authentication technology, enterprise WeChat application development, enterprise log service platform technology, call chain tracking technology, message queue RabbitMQ, big data platform development technology, master data solution tool platform, Spring Boot/Spring Cloud, Vue.js, Alibaba Cloud, AWS, microservice container Docker, Kubernetes (K8s), GitLab Cl/CD, Robot Framework API automation, web UI automation, and app UI automation.

Awards: I have been repeatedly praised by both the business department and the company management team.

Shanghai ALO7 Technology Co., Ltd. Software Development Expert | December 2017 - August 2021

Responsibilities: I was responsible for the key online teaching system development (including scheduling courses, managing user problem tickets, and creating teacher payment modules) and the Automation Platform (to support online time sheeting, contract approval, IT help desk, and automation testing processes). I communicated with the BA team to understand their business requirements, took ownership of all outstanding deliverables (designing solutions, coding, testing, and creating technical documents), and researched advanced technologies to discover the best practices and then drove those best practices within the team.

Skills: Cloud service migration from Amazon to Alibaba, Java-based component development, Redis cache optimization, GitLab CI/CD tools, and Docker image development, and JHipster full-stack platform.

Awards: I got promoted twice after achieving good performance within the team.

Omni Prime Inc.

Automation Testing Architect | October 2016 - December 2017

Responsibilities: I Worked on the Internet Finance online system (peer-to-peer lending), I was responsible for building and developing an automation test strategy, framework, and tool platform. I worked on basic services such as gateways, service registration discovery, load-balancing, permissions, security, control center, dictionary, SMS platform, and other modules. I have a deep understanding of microservice interface testing, integration testing, contract testing, component testing, Docker web UI testing, App Cloud testing, and more.

Skills: Python, Robot Framework, Vue.js, Docker, Jenkins, GitLab CI/CD Pipeline, CI/CD.

Awards: I got a promotion in six months for my outstanding achievement.

Pactera Technology Co. Ltd.

Senior Delivery Manager | May 2008 - October 2016

Responsibilities: I worked on the Home and Small Business Server testing project, where I was responsible for creating a test strategy, a test plan, and delivering tests such as designing test cases, executing tests, making test reports, and submitting bugs. Test management included managing resources, risks, schedules, stakeholders, training, and more.

Skills: Set up the Microsoft server and client machines, configure service components such as Exchange mail server, Azure cloud storage, Hyper-V, system backup and restoration, and end-to-end automated testing.

Awards: I received the Excellent Employee Award three times, and my team was recognized as one of the top teams.

Augmentum, Inc.

Software Development Engineer in Test | July 2007 - May 2008

Responsibilities: I worked on a Microsoft ERP product, Dynamics AX testing project, where I was responsible for requirement analysis, high-level and low-level design of test cases, review of test cases, coding of automation scripts, submission and tracking of defects, preparation of test reports, knowledge sharing, and documentation of test cases.

Skills: C#, Dynamics AX, Microsoft Test Tool (MTT), Product Studio (bug management)